Amanda Zapata

Orlando, FL

Email: amandazapata802@gmail.com. Phone: (407) 844-3730

https://www.linkedin.com/in/zapamanda/

POSITION OBJECTIVE

Seeking a challenging entry-level position in business or technical communication that lets me apply my core skills in informative and persuasive communication as well as training to add business value for my employer.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Highly motivated self-starter with excellent bilingual verbal, written, and online communication skills. Self-taught in the basics of technical communication and pursuing professional development opportunities within the Society for Technical Communication (STC). Experience as an English teacher has honed leadership, project management, organizational, and interpersonal skills. Proficient in a broad range of business software including online collaborative writing tools; also skilled and versatile in social media.

KEY ATTRIBUTES

CORE SKILLS	TECHNOLOGY SKILLS
 Common-sense, logical problem-solving approach Excellent verbal, written, and online communication skills. Efficient project management and multi-tasking Keen organizational and analytical skills and intuitive task prioritization Bilingual: English and Spanish Exceptional leadership Focused attention to details and data attributes Skilled educator/trainer with proven track record Multimedia experience to create and edit communications in strategic and effective media 	 Proficient in a wide range of business software applications including the Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Outlook) Conversant with XML and HTML at beginner level Experienced in hosting websites on GitHub Experienced on collaborative online work environments such as SharePoint Familiar with Windows 10 operating system/applications Accomplished with online collaborative writing tools such as Zoom and Teams Experienced in graphic design and programs Capable user with search engines

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS AND TRAINING

- Active member, Florida Chapter of STC
 - Staff writer for chapter newsletter, Memo to Members
 - Attend monthly educational chapter meetings on a wide range of technical communication topics
 - Enrolled in a widely acclaimed professional-to-student mentoring program sponsored by the Florida Chapter of STC and the Future Technical Communicators (FTC) organization at UCF.
- Completing a rigorous 20-hour skills-building industry training course in technical writing as part of the mentoring program. Mentor is an STC Fellow with 40 years' experience in technical communication and has taught this course and elements thereof in both industry and academic environments.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

7th Grade English Teacher

8/2023-Present

Maitland Middle School, Orange County Public Schools, Florida

- Work effectively in a dynamic environment requiring shifting priorities with tight deadlines
- Maintain schedule and look-ahead in accordance with state requirements
- Research, review, analyze, and produce metrics for state requirements

- Demystify for students' complex topics and subjects (e.g., literacy, comprehension, grammar, overall writing)
- Use Performance Matters and related product data management systems
- Conduct quality review of materials on curriculum and student work

9th Grade English Teacher

08/2021-5/2023

Saint Cloud High School, Osceola County District Schools, Florida

- Significantly increased student performance on exams as reflected in data attributes
- Provided detailed written communication to parents regarding student success and milestones
- Navigated educational technology in the classroom such as Office 365 products to promote problem-solving skills by editing and revising essays.

Student Teacher Internship

09/2020-5/2021

Orange County Public Schools and Florida Virtual School (UCF Program), Florida

- Improved student performance by assisting mentor, tutoring students 1-on-1 with copywriting and editing tasks
- Provided simultaneous supervision in a fast-paced environment to increase engagement with over 100+ inperson and online students in a hybrid setting using Zoom and Teams
- Utilized Google Sheets to track student and parent communication and increased overall communication

Siemens Energy Summer Work Experience Internship

05/2018-07/2018

Orlando, FL

- Assigned documents and drawing identifiers to comply contractual and legal requirements
- Collaborated with managers, engineers, and other personnel to research, analyze, and create solutions for configuration, tracking, and traceability
- Coordinated and validated documentation with internal and external customers
- Created documentation and templates to meet business requirements in compliance with specifications, standards, and formats, including APA and MLA
- Acquired subject knowledge by interviewing product developers, observing performance of production methods, and referring to specifications, illustrations, and trade journals
- Oversaw preparation of illustrative materials, diagrams, and charts
- Authored, edited, and analyzed technical information and publications in preparation for document release and implementation

EDUCATION

- AA degree in General Studies with honors, Valencia College, Orlando, FL: May 2019: 3.8 cumulative GPA, 3 times on *President's List*, four times on *Dean's List*
- **B.A degree in Secondary Education (English Language Arts)**, University of Central Florida 3.9 GPA | *UCF Top Ten Knight* | *Dean's List every semester*

COMMUNITY SERVICE AFFILIATIONS	
✓ Animal Shelter Volunteer, Saint Cloud, FL	✓ Osceola County School District and
✓ Give Kids the World Angel Volunteer	Orange County Public Schools volunteer

PORTFOLIO: https://azapata11.github.io/zapata/

REFERENCES: Available upon request